<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Megalith.rocks</title><link>https://megalith.rocks/</link><description>Recent content on Megalith.rocks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://megalith.rocks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Homelab</title><link>https://megalith.rocks/posts/homelab/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://megalith.rocks/posts/homelab/</guid><description>This is a crosspost of my Reddit post on r/homelab. It&amp;rsquo;s about my homelab I built during fall 2021. First off, it basically consists of three parts. First and most important is the OSPF backbone that runs on top of three site-to-site IPsec VPN tunnels. These tunnels are powered by Strongswan running on a VPS, an EdgeRouter and a Juniper SRX300.
The second layer, if you will, runs all core infrastructure services such as DNS (authoritative and recursors), PXE boot using TFTP and nginx, LDAP multi master and DHCP.</description></item><item><title>Peak District</title><link>https://megalith.rocks/posts/peak-district/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://megalith.rocks/posts/peak-district/</guid><description>On Monday the 11th of November 2019 I set out to Ijmuiden (NL) to hop on the ferry to Newcastle. From there I&amp;rsquo;d catch the intercity train to Sheffield where I&amp;rsquo;d change to a regional train that&amp;rsquo;d take me to Heathersage. A couple degrees Celsius above zero, it was apparent fall had set in on the English midlands.
Starting on my bike tour Wednesday morning, I had about 70 kilometers of mountainbike trails ahead of me.</description></item><item><title>Ardennes Arbalete</title><link>https://megalith.rocks/posts/ardennes-arbalete/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://megalith.rocks/posts/ardennes-arbalete/</guid><description>In July 2019 I hopped on the train to Maastricht to start my first proper bikepacking trip on my ECR. The Ardennes Arbalete sparked my interest months prior. I just got my Surly ECR in May, and went for an overnighter in the Veluwe (NL) in June. Hence, I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite know what to expect on a multi-day tour. Questions like; How will the bike hold up? Will the powerbank have enough juice?</description></item></channel></rss>